PINE HILLS FORTNIGHTLY CLUB, INC. RECORDS (APAP031) 1898-2003
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Pine Hills Fortnightly Club, Inc. Records1898-2003
nam_apap031
Pine Hills Fortnightly Club, Inc.
2.5
The Pine Hills Fortnightly Club was founded in the Albany, New York area in 1898 by Mary M. Shaw and a group of women as a literary and social club. Members, most of whom are college educated, met on alternate Monday afternoons to deliver papers around a central theme that involves the study of history, literature, and art. The major part of the collection is devoted to the originals or copies of the papers delivered by members at the bi-weekly meetings.
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
Administrative History
The Pine Hills Fortnightly Club was founded by Miss Mary M. Shaw in 1898 as a woman's literary and social club. According to the Club's earliest Constitution, "Its object shall be the study of history, literature and art and the literary and social entertainment of its members" [Original Constitution, ca. 1898, Article II]. The Club was "federated" in 1900 [Folder: Programmes, 1904-1913, Programme 1911-1912, "The Empire State"]. Virtually from the Club's inception, meetings have been held on alternate Monday afternoons, from October 1st through April 30th [ca. 1898 Constitution, Article IX]. In the later Constitutions, the meeting schedule changed to " ... the 2nd and 4th Mondays of each month from October to April inclusive, except the second meeting in December shall be omitted" [1991 Constitution, By-Laws, Article I, Section 1]. Originally the membership was limited to twenty with dues of $.50 annually. By 1901, they allowed the membership to reach fifty. Currently the annual dues are $25.00 and, during the last five years, active membership has averaged twenty.
An Executive Committee of the officers governs the Pine Hills Fortnightly Club: a president, two vice-presidents, recording secretary, corresponding secretary, treasurer, and the Program Committee Chairman. The other standing committees (auditing, membership, house, publicity, telephone, social, yearbook) have a chairman and the Club's president as an ex officio member. In later years, a librarian and historian were added, but there is no current record of those officers. Members are for the most part college-educated, well-read, active and engaged in various professions as is evident from the credentials cited in recommendation-for-membership letters and from the scope and content of the members' papers delivered at meetings.
According to the earliest Constitution, "At the end of each meeting not more than twenty minutes shall be devoted to business" [ca. 1898 Constitution]; later the Constitution raised the time limit but did not exceed thirty minutes [1927 Constitution]. The Club devoted the remaining meeting time, an estimated hour to an hour and a half, to the presentation of a member's paper followed by a discussion among the membership.
The literary focus of the Club's twice-a-month meetings is the presentation of papers. These scholarly papers center on a theme decided upon by the Program Committee as a year-long exploration of a particular topic. Using the available research tools a college-graduate would have at its disposal at the time, members focused on topics such as geographic locations, concepts relating to American historical development, works of fine art of particular periods or artists, and authors and their works. The collection exhibits well-researched papers addressing not only the topics but their possible social and historical ramifications; the presentation of these papers served as a form of continuing education for the membership.
By decade, the topics addressed by Club members are summarized as follows:
1900-1910: foreign countries, such as Holland, Scotland, Italy, Germany, France, and Russia
1911-1920: New York State; studies of America, its progress, its problems, its neighboring countries; a literary study of Shakespeare's women; and China
1921-1930: much literary focus on 20th century modern fiction and verse; general studies in literature; outstanding authors; and American art
1931-1940: eclectic topics of literature; foreign countries; geography; American magazines
1941-1950: global and national concerns regarding democracy; forging global friendships; American idealism; and literary best-selling books in the USA market
1951-1960: decade begins with American topics of "utopias", "folkways", "legends"; and progresses into a concern with the past and history
1961-1970: women; literature; great civilizations; education; Albany; "Island Interlude"
1971-1980: 75 years of Pine Hill Fortnightly; women writers; women pioneers; Africa; Iran; 20th century American literature
1981-1998: Native Americans; small-town America; "Albany and the American Dream"; early America; literature; masterpieces; emerging technologies.
1999-: State parks; islands; hobbies; China
The second part of the Pine Hills Fortnightly Club's constitutional objective is the "...social entertainment of its members". The Club's formal social functions consist of a Spring Luncheon held in May (the end to the Club's administrative year), and a Christmas party held during most years. The Spring Luncheon Programs have included the presentation of the theme for the following year's papers, the presentation of new officers, and the singing of the club song. The luncheon often features a guest speaker or a vocalist. The Christmas party, when held, was often the occasion for a choral reading by members or the singing of Christmas songs.
The Pine Hills Fortnightly Club's mission and membership have changed little throughout the Club's existence.
Scope and Content Information
The Pine Hills Fortnightly Club Records, ca. 1898-2001 (with gaps) include constitutions and by-laws, literary and social events programs and yearbooks, meeting minutes, attendance records, financial data, correspondence, letters of recommendation for candidates' membership, and newspaper clippings about members and other literary clubs that document the membership, history and the primary reasons for the Club's existence. Series 5 includes an account by Club members of their meeting with United Nations General Assembly President Vijaya Lakshmi Pandit of India.
The papers presented by Club members constitute half of the collection. The earliest paper in the collection is dated 1911. Many, but not all, papers listed with undated and no authors may be early presentations because these documents are handwritten with fountain pens. No papers exist in the collection from the 1920s or the 1960s.
Arrangement of the Collection
Divided into 6 file series, some with subseries.
Acquisition Information
The records were received from Eleanor Lattimer, President of the Pine Hills Fortnightly Club, Inc. The initial deposit of records was received by the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, in January 1994. Additional deposits were made in 1997, 1998, 2000, 2001, and 2003 by club members Anne Roberts, Alice Murphy, and Ethel Severinghaus.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Subject and Genre Headings
Pine Hills Fortnightly Club, Inc.; Shaw, Mary M.; Women -- New York (State) -- Albany -- Societies and clubs.; Art -- Societies, etc.; Literature -- Societies, etc.; Clubs -- New York (State) -- Albany.; Constitution.; Bylaws.; Programs.; Yearbooks.; Administrative records.; Financial records.; Neighborhood and Community Associations
Container List
- Constitutions and By-Laws, ca. 1898; 1903; 1927-1991; 1; 0.1
  The collection contains the constitutions for 1898, 1903, and 1927-1991. The Constitution includes Articles, By-Laws, and Amendments. The Club's By-Laws specify the procedure by which new members are proposed. The earliest Pine Hills Fortnightly Club Constitution is handwritten in a notebook followed by the first recording of membership names dated 1900. Included in the constitutions are by-laws, articles, and amendments to the Constitutions. Constitutions often contain hand annotated revisions for incorporation into the next year's constitution.
  - Constitution and By-laws, ca. 1898; 1927-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Programs and Yearbooks, 1904-1913; 1913-2003; 2; 0.66
  Programmes are titled by the Club's annual themes. Programmes and Yearbooks have a copy of the Club Song, list the paper titles and presenter's name, the names of officers and committee members, and a listing of all active members, associate members, nonresident members, honorary members, and members "in memoriam". Beginning in 1921, a list of reference books, or a bibliography associated with the year's theme, became a standard inclusion. Program Committee files describe the formulation of the yearly themes and the provision of direction and guidance for the subject of a member's paper. The Committee assigns the schedule where members commit to delivering a paper at a scheduled meeting.
  - Annual Themes, 1900-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Program Committee Suggestions for Annual Themes and Topics, 1964-1965; 1983-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Programs, 1904-1913 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Yearbooks, 1913-1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Yearbooks, 1927-1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yearbooks, 1941-1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yearbooks, 1956-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Yearbooks, 1976-2003 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Special Event Programs and Anniversary Papers, 1919; 1938; 1943-1948; 1972; 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Spring Luncheon Programs, 1976; 1978; 1981; 1984-1995; 1997-2003 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Administrative Records, 1902-1999; 3; 0.43 29 folders
  - Sub-series 1: Secretary's Files, 1902-1999; 3.1; 0.67 23 folders
    The Recording Secretary's minutes of meetings have some gaps. The earliest recorded minutes in this collection are from 1902. The minutes are generally limited to one or one and a half pages. The minutes record Club activities at their meetings. The number of members present is listed, sometimes along with an attendance list. Next the secretary records the introduction of a topic, the title of the paper, and the presenter. The secretary also records briefly the actions of the business meeting following the presentations. Included also in the Sub-series are the minutes of the Executive Committees meetings for 1910-1923. Attendance records appear as part of Secretary's Minutes, except for a folder of separate attendance entries for 1903-1916 and 1941-1957.
    - Attendance Records, 1903-1916; 1941-1957 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1902-1905 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1905-1909 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1909-1913 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1913-1917 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1917-1922 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1922-1931 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1951-1956 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1956-1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1995-1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sub-series 2: Correspondence, 1945-1997; 3.2; 0.10 3 folders
    The Correspondence sub-series includes notes and correspondence regarding the disposition of the Club's archival records; informal and social correspondence; and letters regarding meeting sites; and correspondence with the printing company which printed yearbooks, and programs.
    - Archival Disposition of Records, Correspondence, 1988-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1971; 1972; 1973; 1986-1988; 1999 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Printing Correspondence, 1945-1954 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Sub-series 3: Committee Files, 1910-1988; 3.3; 0.10 3 folders
    This sub-series includes records from the executive committee and the membership committee. Included in membership files are membership recommendations with the credentials of a proposed member (college[s] attended, professional development, posts held, awards won). Some recommendation letters also include the credentials of the proposed member's husband. See also Series 1: Programmes and Yearbooks for records of the Program Committee.
    - Duties of Committees, ca. 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Executive Committee Meetings and copy of Robert's Rules of Order, 1910-1923 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Membership Recommendations, ca. 1944-1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Financial Records, 1913-1922; 1928-1969; 1992-2003; 4; 0.15 4 folders
  Bound ledgers record the expenses of the club's activities and printing fees. Dues records are kept in the ledgers, along with "fines" before the club ceased the fining system. This series also includes budget proposals for 1990-1993 and the Treasurer's Report of 1994.
  - Budget Ledgers, 1913-1922; 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Budget Ledgers, 1928-1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Budget Ledgers, 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Budget Proposal, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Subject Files, 1900-1997; 5; 0.20 18 folders
  Subject files include memorials, news clippings, plays presented, and press notices. There are memorials and tributes to some deceased members illustrating aspects of the social ties among the women, as well as news clippings about members and their families. Other news clippings illustrate the Club's relation to the community and the nature of long-lived literary clubs. News clippings are included in the folder that records the 1953 visit of twenty-three Club members to the United Nations to meet the first woman ever to be elected President of the General Assembly, Madam Vijaya Lakshmi Pandit, as well as a transcript of the interview they conducted with President Pandit.
  - Guest Day, Photographs, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Memorial for Member Ruth Birdseye (1904-1993), 1993 September 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Memorial for Member Martha Decker (1892-1985), "Miss Decker", from Girls Academy, publication of Albany Academy Girls, ca. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Memorial for Member Lillian A. Johnson, (1905-2003), 2003 May 25 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Memorial for Member Edith Owen Wallace (1896-1972), 1972 February 19 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - News Clipping, "Literary clubs live on--but for how long?" Albany, NY Times Union, 1980 February 24 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - News Clipping, "Church council names director" on Gladys and Jim Snedeker, Albany, NY Times Union, 1986 June 12 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - News Clipping, "Former Librarian's Portrait is Unveiled", on Alice Murphy. Albany, NY Times Union, 1972 February 15 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - News Clipping, "90 Years is a very long time" on 90th anniversary of Thursday Morning Club, Troy, NY The Sunday Record, 1994 May 6 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Plays Presented, 1960s; Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Press Notices, 1937-1938; 1942; 1949; 1963-1967; Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Reading of First Meeting, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Visit to United Nations, Interview with General Assembly President Vijaya Lakshmi Pandit, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Papers Presented, 1911-1984; 6; 0.78
  The author's name, the title of the paper, the date of presentation, and notation of any illustrations that may accompany a paper are included for each paper. Dates were identified from the actual paper, from the listing in Programmes and Yearbooks, or from secretary's minutes. A number of papers are titled but do not identify author or date presented.
  There are 17 mounted illustrations in Box 2 to accompany papers.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - "Empire State: Social Life and Customs--1609-64", no author, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "New England Poetry", by Frances V. Hubbard, 1933 February (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "Novel:The Scottish Queen, " no author, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "Don Quixote and Cervantes", no author, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "The Lady of Godey's", no author, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - "The Women of South America", no author, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "Handicaps and Triumphs of the Moslem Woman", by June Bowen, 1954 February (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - "Passions of the Mind (Freud) by Irving Stone", by Mrs. Taylor, 1972 January 24 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - "Ellen Browning Scripps", by Mrs. Taylor, 1975 January 13 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "Folk Art", by Mrs. Taylor, 1976 October 25 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - "All of Time Is Still One History: Guy Davenport", by Mrs. Taylor, 1979 April 23 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "Emily Carr: Artist of the Canadian West Coast", by Georgiana Taylor, 1981 February 23 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - "Roger Fry/ Duncan Grant", by Mrs. Taylor, 1984 February 27 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - "Bertrand Russell", by Mabel E. Jackman, 1984 April 23 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - "Sinclair Lewis: Gopher Prairie to Nobel Prize", by Elizabeth Slagle, 1985 March 11 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - "The French Canadians: The Northern Flood", by Winifred Gibson, 1986 January 13 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "The Political Connection", by Mrs. Taylor, 1986 February 24 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - "Eastern European Immigrants to Albany: Poles, Russians, Ukrainian, Armenians", by Charity M. Roth, 1986 March 31 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - "The New Immigration: Hispanics and the Pacific Rim", by Mabel E. Jackman, 1986 April 14 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - "The Spanish Main", by Gladys Snedeker, 1987 January 12 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - "The Massachusetts Delegation to the Constitutional Convention of 1787", by Charity Roth, 1987 October 26 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - "The Delegates from New Jersey", by Rhoda Castor, 1988 January 11 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - "The Delegates from Pennsylvania", by Mrs. Robert Clarke, 1988 January 25 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - "The Delegates from Delaware and Maryland", by Irene Walker, 1988 February 8 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - "The Men Who Made the Constitution: A Bicentennial Portfolio", by Georgiana Taylor, 1988 February 22 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - "The Delegates from Virginia", by Mrs. Taylor, 1988 February 22 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - "The Finished Work", by Ruth A. Birdseye, 1988 April 25 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - "Thrills and Chills: Gothic-Evil Occult", by Eleanor Lattimer, 1988 November 28 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - "Novel Approaches: Discovering the Formula, Murder They Wrote", by Marion Motisher, 1988 November 29 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - "Entertaining Angels Unaware, Ghost Stories--Good Occult", by Gladys Snedeker, 1988 December 12 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - "Satire: Lord, What Fools These Mortals Be", by Lois V.Williams, 1989 January 8 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - "Check Your Valuables: Picaresque Fiction", by Ethel Long Severinghaus, 1989 January 23 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - "From The Bookish Brothers Grimm, A Flood of Fantasy, (Kathleen Burke, Smithsonian, May 1986): Once Upon a Time", by Betty Slagle, 1989 February 13 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - "Listen, my children", by Marion E. Mayfield-Johnson, 1989 February 27 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - "A Tale of Two Cities", by Mary G. Coggin, 1989 March 27 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - "Animal Stories", by Doris Welsh, 1989 April 24 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - "Constantinople", by Evelyn Jenkins, 1989 October 9 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - "Minoan Crete", by Lillian Johnson, 1989 November 13 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - "Xi'an: Ancient Capital of China", by Winifred Gibson, 1989 December 11 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - "1950-60: The Suburban Woman as Viewed by Betty Friedan", by Doris Welsh, 1989+ (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - "CLUNY: To the Glory of God", by Barbara Rau, 1990 January 22 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - "Regarding Venice", by Mary Ellen Stewart, 1990 February 20 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - "Paris in the Seventeenth Century: King Louis XIV and the Population", by Rhoda Castor, 1990 March 26 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - "Peter the Great: The Man and his Impact on Russia", (Pictures and Notes on Peter the Great) by Charity Roth, 1990 April 9 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - "London: The Victorian Period", (3 illus.) by Georgiana Taylor, 1990 April 23 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - "The Arts of Poland", by Ethel Severinghaus, 1990 October 22 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - "(Alva Nurierz) Cabeza de Vaga", by Evelyn Jenkins, 1991 January 1 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - "The Madwoman of Chaillot by Jean Giraudoux", 1991 January 28 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    (play reading) Cast members: Alice Murphy, Rhoda Castor, Georgiana Taylor, Doris Welsh, Hilda Olivo, Betty Slagle, Marion Mothisher, Lillian Johnson, Frances Allee.
  - "The City of Dresden", by Mrs. Lattimer, 1991 January 14 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - "The Gypsies", by Mrs. Welsh, 1991 May 13 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - "Christopher Columbus", by Charity Roth, 1991 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - "Western Star by Stephen Vincent Benet" (choral reading), 1991 December 9 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - "Henry Hudson: Magnificent Failure/Samuel de Champlain: Father of New France", by Georgiana Taylor (14 illus), 1992 February 10 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - "Edith Wharton: The Many Faceted Woman", by Ethel Severinghaus, 1992 November 23 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - "The Fox at the Manger", (Christmas reading) directed by Marion Thortenson, 1992 December 14 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Charlotte Bronte", by Doris Welsh, 1993 March 8 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Leonardo da Vinci's The Last Supper, " by Betty Slagle. "The Pyramids", by Mrs. Melius, 1993 March 22 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Robert Oppenheimer, Father of the Atom Bomb", 1993 November 8 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Also: "Peggy Church's Dream" from Peggy Pond Church's The House at Otowi Bridge, by Charity Roth.
  - "The Masterpiece:Carmen, and How it Came to Be", by Eleanor Clarke, 1993 November 22 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "The Child: John Dewey to Marion Edelman", by Evelyn Jenkins, 1994 January 10 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "The State Capitol and Its Environs", by Georgiana Taylor, 1994 February 14 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Washington Irving and His Friends", by Charity M. Roth, 1994 March 28 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Leonard Bernstein: From the Classics to West Side Story", by Mrs. Rau, 1994 May 9 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "Food in History", by Elizabeth Slagle, 1994 October 24 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Losing Ground", by Charity M. Roth, 1994 November 14 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Festival Foods from Around the World", by Gladys Snedeker, 1994 December 12 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "Food and Trade: National Monopolies on Various Foodstuffs And the Economic Results", by Vera Scadura, 1995 January 10 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Food As Destiny: The Old World Meets the New at the Table", by Eleanor Lattimer, 1995 January 27 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "Food Taboos in Various Cultures", by Charity M. Roth, 1995 April 24 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "Eleanor Roosevelt and the Great Depression", by Charity M. Roth, 1995 November 27 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "Evolution in the Telephone Industry", by Charity M. Roth, 1996 October 14 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - "From the Piggy Bank to the ATM", by Vera Scadura, 1996 November 25 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - "Barbara McClintock, Rosalyn Sussman Yalow, Rachel Carson", by Evelyn Jenkins, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "Women in the Board Room: The Fallout from the Social Movements and the Economic Realities of the Present", by Anne Roberts, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "From The Abacus to the Internet: Computers and Their Implications", by Anne F. Roberts, 1997 April 14 (Box 3, Folder 21)